<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Experiments</title>
    <description>Patrick Ding&#39;s website. A blog with my projects and information about me.
</description>
    <link>http://delimited0.github.io/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://delimited0.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Sat, 08 Oct 2016 21:56:23 -0400</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 08 Oct 2016 21:56:23 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.1.6</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Topic Models for New York Philharmonic Programs</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I have read about applications of topic models beyond text to things like genetic data and image data, but as far as I can tell there hasn’t been much work on topic modeling musical performance data. I think the performance program data from the New York Philharmonic &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/nyphilarchive/PerformanceHistory&quot;&gt;archive&lt;/a&gt; is very amenable to topic modeling. For example you could think of the concerts as being documents, and the pieces performed as being words. Then assume a generative model that draws pieces from a topic-specific distribution of pieces conditional on a latent topic assignment variable, which is itself drawn from a concert-specific topic-distribution parameter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recently I implemented the Topics-Over-Time (TOT) model &lt;a href=&quot;#Wang:2006&quot;&gt;(Wang &amp;amp; McCallum, 2006)&lt;/a&gt; and applied it to New York Philharmonic performances. This model adds an observed timestamp variable for each word, drawn from topic-specific beta distribution conditional on the latent topic, which allows modeling of time dynamics for topics. For this project I did not treat pieces as words, but instead used composers of pieces. This reduces the sparsity of the problem a bit, since composers wrote many pieces but many individual pieces are performed very rarely (no I haven’t checked, but this seems reasonable to me). Also instead of using concerts as documents, I aggregated all the composers’ pieces performed by the same conductor into a document, so that I could analyze per-conductor topic distributions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I fit a 70 topic model using a collapsed Gibbs sampler. I chose 70 topics on the basis of coherence scores &lt;a href=&quot;#Mimno:2011&quot;&gt;(Mimno, Wallach, Talley, Leenders, &amp;amp; McCallum, 2011)&lt;/a&gt; for a variety of topic numbers. Below are four of the inferred topics, with composers ranked in decreasing order of term score, that I found interesting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/2016-10-02-Nyphil-Topics/topic_table.svg&quot; alt=&quot;Topics&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The labels are my interpretation of course. In Musicals/Pops, we see &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Stephen_Sondheim&quot;&gt;Stephen Sondheim&lt;/a&gt; at the top, who is famous for his musical scores. In Opera we see the usual, mainly Italian, suspects like &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Giuseppe_Verdi&quot;&gt;Verdi&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Giacomo_Puccini&quot;&gt;Puccini&lt;/a&gt;. In American we have &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Charles_Ives&quot;&gt;Ives&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/John_Philip_Sousa&quot;&gt;John Phillip Sousa&lt;/a&gt;, the latter of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=a-7XWhyvIpE&quot;&gt;Stars-and-Stripes&lt;/a&gt; fame. Finally I’ve included a topic I call Standard, because it’s filled with stalwarts of the orchestral repertoire. This is the bread and butter of orchestral fare that orchestras everywhere return to time and time again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The TOT model assumes a beta distribution for the normalized timestamp, and estimates them using method-of-moments. Here are the time distribution for the four topics I discussed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/2016-10-02-Nyphil-Topics/topic_time_grid.svg&quot; alt=&quot;topic_time&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The topics are very localized, only American covers much more than a few decades. This is not so desirable, since you would expect topics like opera to be persistent. Especially the standard topic should be present throughout the history. Instead the topics might just correspond to individual conductors, whose careers only last so long. Or there might be some kind of organizational quirk that leads to localized topics, like if a pops series was begun after 1990 or so, leading to the pops topic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For each topic you can see which conductors have the highest probability. For the above topics:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/2016-10-02-Nyphil-Topics/conductor_table.svg&quot; alt=&quot;topic_time&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m not familiar with most of the names here, but you can see that &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Aaron_Copland&quot;&gt;Aaron Copland&lt;/a&gt; has a high probability of conducting American music, which makes sense. Granted that’s because he mostly conducted his own works, see this at my conductor-composer browser &lt;a href=&quot;https://patrickding.shinyapps.io/comp-cond/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. You can see that there are some issues with conductor tokenizing; Andre Previn gets listed twice because of what looks like a unicode issue and sometimes multiple conductors are listed for one piece performed, as with &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Claudio_Abbado&quot;&gt;Claudio Abbado&lt;/a&gt; and friends in the American category.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The TOT paper also describes how you can calculate topic distribution mixtures over time:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/2016-10-02-Nyphil-Topics/topic_dist.svg&quot; alt=&quot;topic_time&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The four topics discussed above are pops (29), opera (52), American (45), and standard (26). There are relatively few topics early on, and then many after about 1930. Partly that’s because the NY phil didn’t have as many performances in the nineteenth century. But perhaps it also reflects an increase in programming diversity in the twentieth century, due to conductor preferences and/or general musical trends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope you enjoyed the pretty plots, but there are quite a few issues with the application of TOT to this kind of data. Most importantly I’m not even using all the data available; ideally I’d also model pieces played, not just composers, so that we could allow for topics that favor certain pieces for the same composer. Another issue is that topic modeling does not work so well for shorter documents (see this &lt;a href=&quot;http://stats.stackexchange.com/questions/25558/topic-models-for-short-documents&quot;&gt;question&lt;/a&gt; on stats.stackexchange), and concert programs are all very short, usually with fewer than 10 pieces performed. There has been some work on directly modeling word co-occurence &lt;a href=&quot;#Yan:2013&quot;&gt;(Yan, Guo, Lan, &amp;amp; Cheng, 2013)&lt;/a&gt; in shorter documents that leads to good results, and I think it might be effective for this kind of data.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 02 Oct 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://delimited0.github.io/music,/nyphil/2016/10/02/Nyphil-Topics.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://delimited0.github.io/music,/nyphil/2016/10/02/Nyphil-Topics.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>music,</category>
        
        <category>nyphil</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>New York Philharmonic Conductors</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In January the New York Philharmonic &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nytimes.com/2016/01/28/arts/music/new-york-philharmonic-taps-jaap-van-zweden-as-its-next-maestro.html?action=click&amp;amp;contentCollection=Music&amp;amp;module=RelatedCoverage&amp;amp;region=Marginalia&amp;amp;pgtype=article&quot;&gt;appointed&lt;/a&gt; Jaap van Zweden as its next music director. According to the various news and magazine articles about the announcement, van Zweden seems to be more inclined toward Beethoven, Brahms, and other classical music meat-and-potatoes composers compared to his current director Alan Gilbert.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What does the data say? Some months ago the New York Philharmonic posted its historical performance data to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/nyphilarchive/PerformanceHistory&quot;&gt;Github&lt;/a&gt;. van Zweden hasn’t had that many performances with the New York phil yet, so unfortunately the archive won’t have much to say about his repertoire choices. We can use it though to get a sense of the artistic choices of the many conductors of the orchestra through its long history and see which composers’ pieces they tended to perform.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wrote a &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Shiny&lt;/code&gt; app that allows you to see the top N composers performed by each conductor with the New York Philharmonic, availble &lt;a href=&quot;https://patrickding.shinyapps.io/comp-cond/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. For example, here’s Alan Gilbert’s top 15 composers:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/2016-08-14-Nyphil-Composer-Conductor/gilbert.svg&quot; alt=&quot;Gilbert&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He has actually played Tchaikovsky with the NY Phil more than 125 times, and there are many Romantic-era stalwarts on this list. But in support of Gilbert’s reputation for forward-looking programming, &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Christopher_Rouse_(composer)&quot;&gt;Christopher Rouse&lt;/a&gt; is his 10th most conducted composer. The composer called “Anthem” is not a person, I believe it’s just the National Anthem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How about the NY Phil’s most famous (arguably) conductor?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/2016-08-14-Nyphil-Composer-Conductor/bernstein.svg&quot; alt=&quot;Bernstein&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;His list looks rather patriotic, with 5 Americans in his top 15. He conducted &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Aaron_Copland&quot;&gt;Copland&lt;/a&gt; with the orchestra more than 150 times, and of course he played a lot of his own works. We also see that he performed Mahler about 125 times; he was a major proponent of the composer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Try out the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Shiny&lt;/code&gt; app and let me know if you have any comments.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 14 Aug 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://delimited0.github.io/music,/nyphil/2016/08/14/Nyphil-Composer-Conductor.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://delimited0.github.io/music,/nyphil/2016/08/14/Nyphil-Composer-Conductor.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>music,</category>
        
        <category>nyphil</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Topic Modeling the Daily Princetonian</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;One of my favorite ways to waste time is reading internet comments. You can observe all kinds of angry people there and wonder at their pathologies. While I was still in school I particularly enjoyed reading the comments section of the &lt;em&gt;Daily Princetonian&lt;/em&gt; because of its relevance to me. Though I only worked for a brief time formatting the print edition of the paper, I got to know some of the journalists, opinion writers, and editors through that work and through classes. Writing for a college newspaper requires a thick skin; the commenters are almost always out to get you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At some point I decided I would try to learn something about internet news and comments, perhaps so I could convince myself all those hours were not wasted. A basic question we can ask about news and comments is what are the paper and readers talking about? This kind of question, of what topics underly a corpus, is what probabilistic topic modeling can help answer. A frequently used method for topic modeling is latent Dirichlet allocation &lt;a href=&quot;#Blei:2003&quot;&gt;(Blei, Ng, &amp;amp; Jordan, 2003)&lt;/a&gt;. There have been many extensions to this original model, including some that focus on internet posts and their comments. In this post I describe a model introduced in &lt;a href=&quot;#Yano:2009&quot;&gt;(Yano, Cohen, &amp;amp; Smith, 2009)&lt;/a&gt; and apply it to a corpus of Daily Princetonian articles and their comments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;data&quot;&gt;Data&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I focus in particular on the opinion pieces and letters of the &lt;em&gt;Daily Princetonian&lt;/em&gt; from fall 2013 to spring 2015–opinion pieces because in my experience these columns tend to attract the most, and the most rabid, comments, and that timespan because the &lt;em&gt;Prince&lt;/em&gt; migrated its content to Wordpress in spring 2013 and all comments from before then have been lost. Using &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;beautifulsoup&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Selenium&lt;/code&gt; I scraped 962 articles from the opinion section with a total of 3576 comments. Using the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;tm&lt;/code&gt; package in &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;R&lt;/code&gt; I removed capitalization, whitespace, numbers, and punctuation, stemmed the words using the Porter stemmer &lt;a href=&quot;#Porter:1980&quot;&gt;(Porter, 1980)&lt;/a&gt;, and converted the documents to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bag-of-words_model&quot;&gt;bag of words&lt;/a&gt; representation required by Latent Dirichlet allocation. The data used in this analysis, as well the code for the model, is available at my repo &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/delimited0/comment_type_topic_model&quot;&gt;comment_type_topic_model&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;model&quot;&gt;Model&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#Yano:2009&quot;&gt;(Yano, Cohen, &amp;amp; Smith, 2009)&lt;/a&gt; describe this model as LinkLDA. I do not use the other model they propose, CommentLDA, because it depends on commenter identity. The Disqus commenting system that the Prince uses allows guest commenters who can use anything as their usernames; thus it’s not possible to identify guests, who posted about 40% of the comments I consider here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The generative process of the model is:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;script type=&quot;math/tex; mode=display&quot;&gt;% &lt;![CDATA[
\begin{align*}
	\theta_d &amp;\vert \alpha \sim Dirichlet(\alpha) \\
	z_{dn} &amp;\vert \theta_d \sim Multinomial(\theta_d) \\
	\beta_k &amp;\vert \eta \sim Dirichlet(\eta) \\
	w_{dn} &amp;\vert z_{dn}, \beta \sim Multinomial(\beta_{z_{dn}}) \\\
	z&#39;_{dcn} &amp;\vert \theta_d \sim Multinomial(\theta_d) \\
	\beta&#39;_k &amp;\vert \eta&#39; \sim Dirichlet(\eta&#39;) \\
	w&#39;_{dcn} &amp;\vert z&#39;_{dcn}, \beta&#39; \sim Multinomial(\beta&#39;_{z&#39;_{dcn}})
\end{align*} %]]&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;where &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;w_{dn}&lt;/script&gt; is the &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;n&lt;/script&gt;th observed word in article &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;d&lt;/script&gt;, &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;z_{dn}&lt;/script&gt; is the latent topic assignment of &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;w_{dn}&lt;/script&gt;, &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;\theta_d&lt;/script&gt; is the topic proportion parameter of article &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;D&lt;/script&gt;, &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;w&#39;_{dcn}&lt;/script&gt; is the &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;n&lt;/script&gt;th observed word in comment &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;c&lt;/script&gt; in article &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;d&lt;/script&gt;, &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;z&#39;_{dcn}&lt;/script&gt; is the latent topic assignment of &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;w&#39;_{dcn}&lt;/script&gt;, &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;\beta_k&lt;/script&gt; is the article distribution over words of topic &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;k&lt;/script&gt;, &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;\beta&#39;_k&lt;/script&gt; is the comment distribution over words of topic &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;k&lt;/script&gt;, and &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;\eta&lt;/script&gt;, &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;\eta&#39;&lt;/script&gt;, and &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;\alpha&lt;/script&gt; are the Dirichlet prior parameters for &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;\beta_k&lt;/script&gt;, &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;\beta&#39;_k&lt;/script&gt;, and &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;\theta_d&lt;/script&gt;, respectively.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And in plate notation:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/2016-07-04-Daily-Prince-Actm/actm-gm.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Model in plate notation&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I implemented a collapsed Gibbs sampler for the model with &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Rcpp&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;article-and-comment-topics&quot;&gt;Article and Comment Topics&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At first I was going to choose the number of topics K in some disciplined way, like evaluating based on held out &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Perplexity&quot;&gt;perplexity&lt;/a&gt;, but that requires various approximations and I got lazy. So I just settled on 40 topics. I ran 2000 iterations of the Gibbs sampler. I used the term score metric described in &lt;a href=&quot;#Blei:2009&quot;&gt;(Blei &amp;amp; Lafferty, 2009)&lt;/a&gt; to determine an order for topic visualization. What follows are 10 topics I found coherent and interesting. I list the words that are among the 20 highest by term score in both the article and comment versions of the topic to give a sense of topic identity. I also take the difference between article and comment term scores and list the words with the greatest difference to convey which words are most likely to appear in articles rather than in comments for the same topic. Likewise I use the difference between comment and article scores to illustrate which words are most likely to appear for comments rather than articles. I have labeled each topic myself, based on my own judgment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;panel-group&quot; id=&quot;accordion&quot; role=&quot;tablist&quot; aria-multiselectable=&quot;true&quot;&gt;

  &lt;div class=&quot;panel panel-default&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;panel-heading&quot; role=&quot;tab&quot; id=&quot;headingOne&quot;&gt;
      &lt;h4 class=&quot;panel-title&quot;&gt;
        &lt;a role=&quot;button&quot; data-toggle=&quot;collapse&quot; data-parent=&quot;#accordion&quot; href=&quot;#collapseOne&quot; aria-expanded=&quot;true&quot; aria-controls=&quot;collapseOne&quot;&gt;
          Israel-Palestine
        &lt;/a&gt;
      &lt;/h4&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div id=&quot;collapseOne&quot; class=&quot;panel-collapse collapse&quot; role=&quot;tabpanel&quot; aria-labelledby=&quot;headingOne&quot;&gt;
      &lt;div class=&quot;panel-body&quot;&gt;
      	&lt;table class=&quot;topictable&quot;&gt; 
      		&lt;tr&gt;
      			&lt;td&gt;Both&lt;/td&gt;
      			&lt;td&gt;israel, palestinian, jew, isra, jewish, peac, gaza, call&lt;/td&gt;
      		&lt;/tr&gt;
      		&lt;tr&gt;
      			&lt;td&gt;Article&lt;/td&gt;
      			&lt;td&gt;divest, hillel, cjl, jewish, referendum, conflict, must, action, professor, compani, letter, petit, empha, faculti, support, gaza, profit, quo, two, falk&lt;/td&gt;
      		&lt;/tr&gt;
      		&lt;tr&gt;
      			&lt;td&gt;Comment&lt;/td&gt;
      			&lt;td&gt;jew, arab, right, land, israel, world, kill, muslim, will, polici, bds, egypt, ethnic, govern, human, offer, open, clean, war, state&lt;/td&gt;
      		&lt;/tr&gt;
      	&lt;/table&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;

  &lt;div class=&quot;panel panel-default&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;panel-heading&quot; role=&quot;tab&quot; id=&quot;headingTwo&quot;&gt;
      &lt;h4 class=&quot;panel-title&quot;&gt;
        &lt;a role=&quot;button&quot; data-toggle=&quot;collapse&quot; data-parent=&quot;#accordion&quot; href=&quot;#collapseTwo&quot; aria-expanded=&quot;true&quot; aria-controls=&quot;collapseTwo&quot;&gt;
          Eating Clubs
        &lt;/a&gt;
      &lt;/h4&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div id=&quot;collapseTwo&quot; class=&quot;panel-collapse collapse&quot; role=&quot;tabpanel&quot; aria-labelledby=&quot;headingTwo&quot;&gt;
      &lt;div class=&quot;panel-body&quot;&gt;
      	&lt;table class=&quot;topictable&quot;&gt; 
      		&lt;tr&gt;
      			&lt;td&gt;Both&lt;/td&gt;
      			&lt;td&gt;club, bicker, eat, member, system, friend, join, hose, social, cultur, independ, altern&lt;/td&gt;
      		&lt;/tr&gt;
      		&lt;tr&gt;
      			&lt;td&gt;Article&lt;/td&gt;
      			&lt;td&gt;referendum, vote, conver, eat, institut, process, prospect, altern, social, particip, sophomor, bicker, arbitrari, space, better, decid, end, major, measur, facilit&lt;/td&gt;
      		&lt;/tr&gt;
      		&lt;tr&gt;
      			&lt;td&gt;Comment&lt;/td&gt;
      			&lt;td&gt;peopl, offer, princ, experi, sign, best, discuss, opinion, open, shame, affili, board, exclus, club, comment, late, aid, fix, guarant, hang&lt;/td&gt;
      		&lt;/tr&gt;
      	&lt;/table&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;

  &lt;div class=&quot;panel panel-default&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;panel-heading&quot; role=&quot;tab&quot; id=&quot;headingThree&quot;&gt;
      &lt;h4 class=&quot;panel-title&quot;&gt;
        &lt;a role=&quot;button&quot; data-toggle=&quot;collapse&quot; data-parent=&quot;#accordion&quot; href=&quot;#collapseThree&quot; aria-expanded=&quot;true&quot; aria-controls=&quot;collapseThree&quot;&gt;
          Sexism
        &lt;/a&gt;
      &lt;/h4&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div id=&quot;collapseThree&quot; class=&quot;panel-collapse collapse&quot; role=&quot;tabpanel&quot; aria-labelledby=&quot;headingThree&quot;&gt;
      &lt;div class=&quot;panel-body&quot;&gt;
      	&lt;table class=&quot;topictable&quot;&gt; 
      		&lt;tr&gt;
      			&lt;td&gt;Both&lt;/td&gt;
      			&lt;td&gt;sexism, joke, catcal, sexist, microaggress&lt;/td&gt;
      		&lt;/tr&gt;
      		&lt;tr&gt;
      			&lt;td&gt;Article&lt;/td&gt;
      			&lt;td&gt;site, relationship, websit, can, reflect, woman, photo, user, facebook, internet, simpli, consum, exampl, favorit, christian, categori, frequent, isnt, shirt, microaggress&lt;/td&gt;
      		&lt;/tr&gt;
      		&lt;tr&gt;
      			&lt;td&gt;Comment&lt;/td&gt;
      			&lt;td&gt;survey, cultur, offen, frank, taken, blatant, form, class, perpetu, uncomfort, term, trend, sexism, feel, harass, humor, impress, patriarchi, scale, bossi &lt;/td&gt;
      		&lt;/tr&gt;
      	&lt;/table&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;

  &lt;div class=&quot;panel panel-default&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;panel-heading&quot; role=&quot;tab&quot; id=&quot;heading4&quot;&gt;
      &lt;h4 class=&quot;panel-title&quot;&gt;
        &lt;a role=&quot;button&quot; data-toggle=&quot;collapse&quot; data-parent=&quot;#accordion&quot; href=&quot;#collapse4&quot; aria-expanded=&quot;true&quot; aria-controls=&quot;collapse4&quot;&gt;
          Race
        &lt;/a&gt;
      &lt;/h4&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div id=&quot;collapse4&quot; class=&quot;panel-collapse collapse&quot; role=&quot;tabpanel&quot; aria-labelledby=&quot;heading4&quot;&gt;
      &lt;div class=&quot;panel-body&quot;&gt;
      	&lt;table class=&quot;topictable&quot;&gt; 
      		&lt;tr&gt;
      			&lt;td&gt;Both&lt;/td&gt;
      			&lt;td&gt;white, american, black, asian, privileg, race, minor, group, diver, racial, african&lt;/td&gt;
      		&lt;/tr&gt;
      		&lt;tr&gt;
      			&lt;td&gt;Article&lt;/td&gt;
      			&lt;td&gt;experi, diver, american, percent, show, cultur, south, ident, role, defin, grow, asian, countri, person, fresh, famili, communiti, grant, identifi, recognit&lt;/td&gt;
      		&lt;/tr&gt;
      		&lt;tr&gt;
      			&lt;td&gt;Comment&lt;/td&gt;
      			&lt;td&gt;admiss, white, privileg, check, like, male, fortgang, kid, newbi, phrase, look, poor, seek, bodi, racist, base, econom, nativ, conver, legaci&lt;/td&gt;
      		&lt;/tr&gt;
      	&lt;/table&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;

  &lt;div class=&quot;panel panel-default&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;panel-heading&quot; role=&quot;tab&quot; id=&quot;heading5&quot;&gt;
      &lt;h4 class=&quot;panel-title&quot;&gt;
        &lt;a role=&quot;button&quot; data-toggle=&quot;collapse&quot; data-parent=&quot;#accordion&quot; href=&quot;#collapse5&quot; aria-expanded=&quot;true&quot; aria-controls=&quot;collapse5&quot;&gt;
          Criminal Justice
        &lt;/a&gt;
      &lt;/h4&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div id=&quot;collapse5&quot; class=&quot;panel-collapse collapse&quot; role=&quot;tabpanel&quot; aria-labelledby=&quot;heading5&quot;&gt;
      &lt;div class=&quot;panel-body&quot;&gt;
      	&lt;table class=&quot;topictable&quot;&gt; 
      		&lt;tr&gt;
      			&lt;td&gt;Both&lt;/td&gt;
      			&lt;td&gt;drug, applic, system, justic, question, convict, admiss, punish, prison, marijuana&lt;/td&gt;
      		&lt;/tr&gt;
      		&lt;tr&gt;
      			&lt;td&gt;Article&lt;/td&gt;
      			&lt;td&gt;past, admiss, access, candid, alcohol, violat, person, point, legal, privileg, ask, equal, inequ, level, standard, effect, result, scrutini, process, higher&lt;/td&gt;
      		&lt;/tr&gt;
      		&lt;tr&gt;
      			&lt;td&gt;Comment&lt;/td&gt;
      			&lt;td&gt;princeton, reject, serv, crimin, offic, univ, drug, racial, stop, disadvantag, thousand, discriminatori, arrest, discrimin, sentenc, start, alreadi, freedom, non, sell&lt;/td&gt;
      		&lt;/tr&gt;
      	&lt;/table&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;

  &lt;div class=&quot;panel panel-default&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;panel-heading&quot; role=&quot;tab&quot; id=&quot;heading6&quot;&gt;
      &lt;h4 class=&quot;panel-title&quot;&gt;
        &lt;a role=&quot;button&quot; data-toggle=&quot;collapse&quot; data-parent=&quot;#accordion&quot; href=&quot;#collapse6&quot; aria-expanded=&quot;true&quot; aria-controls=&quot;collapse6&quot;&gt;
          The Prince Itself
        &lt;/a&gt;
      &lt;/h4&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div id=&quot;collapse6&quot; class=&quot;panel-collapse collapse&quot; role=&quot;tabpanel&quot; aria-labelledby=&quot;heading6&quot;&gt;
      &lt;div class=&quot;panel-body&quot;&gt;
      	&lt;table class=&quot;topictable&quot;&gt; 
      		&lt;tr&gt;
      			&lt;td&gt;Both&lt;/td&gt;
      			&lt;td&gt;princ, report, articl, news, paper, publish, opinion, write, stori, newspap, comment, journalist, editor&lt;/td&gt;
      		&lt;/tr&gt;
      		&lt;tr&gt;
      			&lt;td&gt;Article&lt;/td&gt;
      			&lt;td&gt;inform, onlin, media, want, reader, public, communiti, sourc, stori, comment, section, communic, content, role, copi, editor, read, edit, tradit, writer&lt;/td&gt;
      		&lt;/tr&gt;
      		&lt;tr&gt;
      			&lt;td&gt;Comment&lt;/td&gt;
      			&lt;td&gt;princ, name, student, piec, report, marcelo, critic, issu, email, insult, serious, dailyprincetoniancom, facebook, hatr, construct, independ, york, alleg, appear, deci&lt;/td&gt;
      		&lt;/tr&gt;
      	&lt;/table&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;

  &lt;div class=&quot;panel panel-default&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;panel-heading&quot; role=&quot;tab&quot; id=&quot;heading7&quot;&gt;
      &lt;h4 class=&quot;panel-title&quot;&gt;
        &lt;a role=&quot;button&quot; data-toggle=&quot;collapse&quot; data-parent=&quot;#accordion&quot; href=&quot;#collapse7&quot; aria-expanded=&quot;true&quot; aria-controls=&quot;collapse7&quot;&gt;
          Mental Health
        &lt;/a&gt;
      &lt;/h4&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div id=&quot;collapse7&quot; class=&quot;panel-collapse collapse&quot; role=&quot;tabpanel&quot; aria-labelledby=&quot;heading7&quot;&gt;
      &lt;div class=&quot;panel-body&quot;&gt;
      	&lt;table class=&quot;topictable&quot;&gt; 
      		&lt;tr&gt;
      			&lt;td&gt;Both&lt;/td&gt;
      			&lt;td&gt;student, health, mental, cps, help, campus&lt;/td&gt;
      		&lt;/tr&gt;
      		&lt;tr&gt;
      			&lt;td&gt;Article&lt;/td&gt;
      			&lt;td&gt;suffer, stress, disea, freshmen, work, servic, percent, health, project, eat, psycholog, balanc, incom, disord, director, habit, serious, mental, dean, campus&lt;/td&gt;
      		&lt;/tr&gt;
      		&lt;tr&gt;
      			&lt;td&gt;Comment&lt;/td&gt;
      			&lt;td&gt;princeton, univ, issu, administr, cps, come, forc, polici, provid, fear, suicid, time, best, need, communic, sign, student, lie, requir, share&lt;/td&gt;
      		&lt;/tr&gt;
      	&lt;/table&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;

  &lt;div class=&quot;panel panel-default&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;panel-heading&quot; role=&quot;tab&quot; id=&quot;heading8&quot;&gt;
      &lt;h4 class=&quot;panel-title&quot;&gt;
        &lt;a role=&quot;button&quot; data-toggle=&quot;collapse&quot; data-parent=&quot;#accordion&quot; href=&quot;#collapse8&quot; aria-expanded=&quot;true&quot; aria-controls=&quot;collapse8&quot;&gt;
          Sexual Assault
        &lt;/a&gt;
      &lt;/h4&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div id=&quot;collapse8&quot; class=&quot;panel-collapse collapse&quot; role=&quot;tabpanel&quot; aria-labelledby=&quot;heading8&quot;&gt;
      &lt;div class=&quot;panel-body&quot;&gt;
      	&lt;table class=&quot;topictable&quot;&gt; 
      		&lt;tr&gt;
      			&lt;td&gt;Both&lt;/td&gt;
      			&lt;td&gt;rape, sexual, assault, victim, sex, consent, campus, case&lt;/td&gt;
      		&lt;/tr&gt;
      		&lt;tr&gt;
      			&lt;td&gt;Article&lt;/td&gt;
      			&lt;td&gt;sexual, violenc, polic, happen, perhap, show, affirm, must, stone, roll, harass, assault, justic, state, vanderbilt, investig, excus, violat, drink, feder&lt;/td&gt;
      		&lt;/tr&gt;
      		&lt;tr&gt;
      			&lt;td&gt;Comment&lt;/td&gt;
      			&lt;td&gt;rape, women, men, fal, woman, evid, parti, accus, man, protect, forc, polici, feminist, drunk, sex, consequ, emot, innoc, behavior, charg&lt;/td&gt;
      		&lt;/tr&gt;
      	&lt;/table&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;

  &lt;div class=&quot;panel panel-default&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;panel-heading&quot; role=&quot;tab&quot; id=&quot;heading9&quot;&gt;
      &lt;h4 class=&quot;panel-title&quot;&gt;
        &lt;a role=&quot;button&quot; data-toggle=&quot;collapse&quot; data-parent=&quot;#accordion&quot; href=&quot;#collapse9&quot; aria-expanded=&quot;true&quot; aria-controls=&quot;collapse9&quot;&gt;
          STEM vs Humanities
        &lt;/a&gt;
      &lt;/h4&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div id=&quot;collapse9&quot; class=&quot;panel-collapse collapse&quot; role=&quot;tabpanel&quot; aria-labelledby=&quot;heading9&quot;&gt;
      &lt;div class=&quot;panel-body&quot;&gt;
      	&lt;table class=&quot;topictable&quot;&gt; 
      		&lt;tr&gt;
      			&lt;td&gt;Both&lt;/td&gt;
      			&lt;td&gt;major, human, art, studi, valu, histori, field, scienc&lt;/td&gt;
      		&lt;/tr&gt;
      		&lt;tr&gt;
      			&lt;td&gt;Article&lt;/td&gt;
      			&lt;td&gt;fact, art, scienc, applic, concentr, explor, liber, scientif, scientist, safe, histori, engin, alumni, career, director, industri, note, warn, taught, technolog&lt;/td&gt;
      		&lt;/tr&gt;
      		&lt;tr&gt;
      			&lt;td&gt;Comment&lt;/td&gt;
      			&lt;td&gt;use, physic, fair, stem, easi, lower, moment, major, pursu, complet, materi, choo, frosh, ongo, valu, author, integr, relax, subject, yeah&lt;/td&gt;
      		&lt;/tr&gt;
      	&lt;/table&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;

  &lt;div class=&quot;panel panel-default&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;panel-heading&quot; role=&quot;tab&quot; id=&quot;heading10&quot;&gt;
      &lt;h4 class=&quot;panel-title&quot;&gt;
        &lt;a role=&quot;button&quot; data-toggle=&quot;collapse&quot; data-parent=&quot;#accordion&quot; href=&quot;#collapse10&quot; aria-expanded=&quot;true&quot; aria-controls=&quot;collapse10&quot;&gt;
          Gender/Sexuality
        &lt;/a&gt;
      &lt;/h4&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div id=&quot;collapse10&quot; class=&quot;panel-collapse collapse&quot; role=&quot;tabpanel&quot; aria-labelledby=&quot;heading10&quot;&gt;
      &lt;div class=&quot;panel-body&quot;&gt;
      	&lt;table class=&quot;topictable&quot;&gt; 
      		&lt;tr&gt;
      			&lt;td&gt;Both&lt;/td&gt;
      			&lt;td&gt;parent, marriag, children, sex, gay, mother&lt;/td&gt;
      		&lt;/tr&gt;
      		&lt;tr&gt;
      			&lt;td&gt;Article&lt;/td&gt;
      			&lt;td&gt;self, piec, dunham, hookup, train, admir, studi, tiger, relationship, live, capac, econom, age, critic, sex, correl, humor, success, good, increa&lt;/td&gt;
      		&lt;/tr&gt;
      		&lt;tr&gt;
      			&lt;td&gt;Comment&lt;/td&gt;
      			&lt;td&gt;coupl, rai, kid, children, biolog, father, will, adopt, orphan, dad, civil, straight, mom, perman, commit, femal, govern, non, deni, logic&lt;/td&gt;
      		&lt;/tr&gt;
      	&lt;/table&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The differences between the article and comment distributions for each topic are interesting but cryptic if you don’t read the &lt;em&gt;Prince&lt;/em&gt;. I have read the &lt;em&gt;Prince&lt;/em&gt; and can offer some insight. In the Israel-Palestine topic for instance, the articles are more likely to discuss events or initiatives related to the conflict, like referenda on whether to divest from Israeli companies. Meanwhile in the comments people focus on identities and emphasize conflict, usually by accusing Israel of being an oppressive apartheid state and accusing Muslims of being hateful killers who want to destroy Israel. In the sexual assault topic, the opinion writers usually decry rape culture, while in the comments people warn against false accusations of rape and blame the victim for being drunk or just regretting poor decisions. Generally the opinion writers are students and relatively liberal in outlook, while many commenters are not even students and often reactionary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;references&quot;&gt;References&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ol class=&quot;bibliography&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;Teh:2007&quot;&gt;Teh, Y. W., Newman, D., &amp;amp; Welling, M. A collapsed variational Bayesian inference algorithm for latent Dirichlet allocation. In &lt;i&gt;In NIPS&lt;/i&gt; (p. 2006).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;Porter:1980&quot;&gt;Porter, M. F. (1980). An algorithm for suffix stripping. &lt;i&gt;Program&lt;/i&gt;, &lt;i&gt;14&lt;/i&gt;(3), 130–137. Retrieved from http://dblp.uni-trier.de/db/journals/program/program14.html#Porter80&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;Blei:2003&quot;&gt;Blei, D. M., Ng, A. Y., &amp;amp; Jordan, M. I. (2003). Latent Dirichlet Allocation. &lt;i&gt;J. Mach. Learn. Res.&lt;/i&gt;, &lt;i&gt;3&lt;/i&gt;, 993–1022. Retrieved from http://dl.acm.org/citation.cfm?id=944919.944937&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;Wang:2006&quot;&gt;Wang, X., &amp;amp; McCallum, A. (2006). Topics over Time: A non-Markov Continuous-time Model of Topical Trends. In &lt;i&gt;Proceedings of the 12th ACM SIGKDD International Conference on Knowledge Discovery and Data Mining&lt;/i&gt; (pp. 424–433). New York, NY, USA: ACM. http://doi.org/10.1145/1150402.1150450&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;Blei:2009&quot;&gt;Blei, D. M., &amp;amp; Lafferty, J. D. (2009). Topic Models.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;Yano:2009&quot;&gt;Yano, T., Cohen, W. W., &amp;amp; Smith, N. A. (2009). Predicting Response to Political Blog Posts with Topic Models. In &lt;i&gt;Proceedings of Human Language Technologies: The 2009 Annual Conference of the North American Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics&lt;/i&gt; (pp. 477–485). Stroudsburg, PA, USA: Association for Computational Linguistics. Retrieved from http://dl.acm.org/citation.cfm?id=1620754.1620824&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;Mimno:2011&quot;&gt;Mimno, D., Wallach, H. M., Talley, E., Leenders, M., &amp;amp; McCallum, A. (2011). Optimizing Semantic Coherence in Topic Models. In &lt;i&gt;Proceedings of the Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing&lt;/i&gt; (pp. 262–272). Stroudsburg, PA, USA: Association for Computational Linguistics. Retrieved from http://dl.acm.org/citation.cfm?id=2145432.2145462&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;Yan:2013&quot;&gt;Yan, X., Guo, J., Lan, Y., &amp;amp; Cheng, X. (2013). A Biterm Topic Model for Short Texts. In &lt;i&gt;Proceedings of the 22Nd International Conference on World Wide Web&lt;/i&gt; (pp. 1445–1456). New York, NY, USA: ACM. http://doi.org/10.1145/2488388.2488514&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jul 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://delimited0.github.io/prince,/topic-models/2016/07/04/Daily-Prince-Actm.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://delimited0.github.io/prince,/topic-models/2016/07/04/Daily-Prince-Actm.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>prince,</category>
        
        <category>topic-models</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
